<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Midd. ss. Ad general. quarterial. sessionem pacis Domini Regis tent. per adjornament pro com. Midd. apud Hicks-Hall in St. John-street in com. prædicto die Veneris, scilicet quarto decimo die Octobris anno regni Regis Caroli Secundi nunc Angliæ, &amp;c. tricesimo tertio.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace (Middlesex)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1681</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B16657</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A464C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.24[36]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R213599</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99884132</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99884132</idno>
            <idno type="VID">189178</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B16657)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 189178)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C15:2[36])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Midd. ss. Ad general. quarterial. sessionem pacis Domini Regis tent. per adjornament pro com. Midd. apud Hicks-Hall in St. John-street in com. prædicto die Veneris, scilicet quarto decimo die Octobris anno regni Regis Caroli Secundi nunc Angliæ, &amp;c. tricesimo tertio.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace (Middlesex)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1681]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Text in English.</note>
                  <note>Orders of 14 Oct. 1681 by the Middlesex Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace concerning Public General Acts 17 Cha.II.c.2 and 22 Cha.II.c.1 against nonconformists and the holding of conventicles.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Laws, etc. (Public general acts) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Dissenters, Religious --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Assembly, Right of --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:189178:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:189178:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon surmounted by a crown and flanked by the English lion and Tudor rose on one side and the Scottish unicorn and thistle on the other</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Mid. ſſ.</dateline>
               <dateline>Ad General. Quarterial. Seſſionem Pacis Domini Regis tent. per Adjornament pro Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> apud <hi>Hicks-Hall</hi> in St. <hi>John-ſtreet</hi> in Com. praedicto <date>die Veneris, ſcilicet Quarto decimo die <hi>Octobris</hi> Anno Regni Regis <hi>Caroli</hi> Secundi nunc <hi>Angliae, &amp;c.</hi>Triceſimo tertio.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>WHEREAS by a Statute made in the Seventeenth year of the Reign of His Majeſty that now is amongſt other things it is enacted, that all ſuch Perſons, who take upon them to Preach in any un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Aſſembly, Conventicle or Meeting, under colour or pretence of any Exerciſe of Religion, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the Laws and Statutes of this Kingdom, ſhall not at any time come within Five miles of a Corporation, nor any perſon teach School, who ſhall not frequent Divine Service eſtabliſhed by the Laws of this Kingdom, as by the ſaid Statute more at large appeareth, under the penalty of Forty pounds for every offence. And whereas by another Statute made in the Two and twentieth year of the Reign of his ſaid Majeſty, it is amongſt other things enacted, That if any perſon of the age of ſixteen years and upwards, ſhall be preſent at any Aſſembly, Meeting, or Conventicle, under colour or pretence of any Exerciſe of Religion, in other manner than according to the Litur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gy and practice of the Church of <hi>England,</hi> where there ſhall be aſſembled five perſons or more, over and beſides thoſe of the Houſhold: And every perſon who ſhall take upon him to preach or teach in any ſuch Meeting, Aſſembly, and Conventicle, ſhall forfeit for every ſuch offence, as in the ſaid Statute is provided: And whereas Papiſts, Seminary Prieſts and Jeſuits may likewiſe in Conventicles and Schools, withdraw his Majeſties Subjects from their Obedience, and corrupt them both in their Religion and duty to his Majeſty; And whereas the Juſtices are informed, that di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers Houſes have been lately erected and built within this County, for ſuch Conventicles and Meetings, and fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented by great numbers of perſons inhabiting in the ſaid County and others, to the great diſturbance of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, and may be of dangerous conſequence, and if not timely ſuppreſſed, ſuch publick Conventicles not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing permitted in any Chriſtian Country; no, not in theſe very Countries where moſt Religions are tollerated; And whereas the Juſtices are likewiſe informed, that divers perſons keep School within the ſaid County contrary to the ſaid Statute, and other Laws, by whom ill principles will be planted in young Children, which will grow up with them, and thereby continue the Separation and Diviſion which is in this Kingdom, to the certain ruine and deſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of his Majeſties Peace and the eſtabliſhed Government. Now for the prevention of the miſchiefs which may ariſe by the ſaid Conventicles and Schools, the Juſtices are of opinion that the ſaid Statutes of the Seventeenth and Two and twentieth of this King ought to be put in due Execution, and do eſteem themſelves obliged by the Oaths which they have taken, to ſee them duly executed; And that they may do, all that in them lies, in order thereunto, They do declare that all Houſe-keepers within this County who keep Alehouſes and other publick houſes for Entertainment by virtue of any Licenſe from the Juſtices of the Peace of this County, and ſhall not go to their Pariſh Church and receive the Sacrament according to the practice in the Church of <hi>England,</hi> and ſhall after the Nine and twentieth day of <hi>October</hi> inſtant go to any ſuch Conventicle as aforeſaid, contrary to the ſaid Statutes, ſhall have their Licences taken from them, and the Houſes of Entertainment ſuppreſſed; and if any ſuch for the future happen to be licenſed, as ſoon as they ſhall be diſcovered, they ſhall likewiſe be ſuppreſſed. The Juſtices further declare, that if the Church-wardens and Overſeers of the Poor, ſhall diſpoſe of any of the Pariſh money by way of Penſion or otherwiſe to poor people who frequent Conventicles, and do not come to their Pariſh Church, and receive the Sacrament there (except in caſe of ſickneſs and neceſſity to be allowed by a Juſtice of Peace) the mony paid to ſuch people ſhall not be allowed by the ſaid Juſtices in the Accounts of the Church-wardens and Overſeers of the Poor, becauſe ſuch perſons who never come to the Pariſh Church ought not to be reckoned of the Pariſh. The Juſtices further declare, that they will appoint ſome fitting perſons to proſecute all Offenders againſt the ſaid Statutes, ſuch publick houſes being the place where factious perſons meet to keep Clubs, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſult together how to diſturb the Government. It is Ordered by this Court, that the aforeſaid Declaration made in Seſſions be publiſhed, that all perſons concerned may take notice of it, and that the Miniſters of each Pariſh in the County be deſired to publiſh it in his Pariſh Church. It is further Ordered, that an humble Addreſs be made to his Majeſty, humbly to beſeech him, in order for better ſettlement of the Peace of this County and his Majeſties eſtabliſhed Government, that all manner of perſons who now are, or hereafter ſhall be, in any Employment in this County under his Majeſty immediately, as likewiſe thoſe who act under them, or by any authority derived by or from them, may be ſuch as go to their Pariſh Church, and receive the Sacrament there according to law. And it is further Ordered, that the Chair-man Sir <hi>George Jeoffryes</hi> wait upon his Majeſty on Saturday morning next with this Addreſs, and that the Juſtices of Peace attend upon him; As likewiſe congratulate with his Majeſty upon his ſafe Return to <hi>London.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>per Cur. <hi>Adderly.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
